我小时候
When I was younger
想做一个牧师
I wanted to be a priest.
和世上的邪恶作战
I was going into battle
拯救人们的灵魂
to save men's souls from the evil of the world.
但随着年龄的增大
But as I got older,
我看到了世界的真实面目
I saw the world for what it really was.
不是我能拯救谁的问题
It wasn't so much who I was going to save,
而是谁能阻止我破坏世界
but who was gonna save the world from me.
（ 二个月以前 ）
? No friends, no jokes, no money ?
?Try to shove me when I'm working my shit ?
? I'll be bringing 'em out, I'm cool ?
? Can't take shit from me in the street ?
? When they come with that beef you know what I'm about... ?
- 他还好吗　- 还行
- How is he? - He's holding up.
你要知道　他很高兴你去看他
You got to know he appreciates you coming to visit.
我知道
Yeah, I know, man.
只是看见爸爸坐牢　心里不舒服
It's just hard seeing your old man sitting in a fucking cage.
我们走
Let's roll.
? Standing out in the rain ?
? I never thought this is where I'd be... ?
真是的　怎么这么多女性杂志
Jesus, what is with all these girlie magazines?
你真的需要吗
I mean really, do you need all this?
- 是的　- 《十招…》
- Yeah, I do. - "10 ways--
- 《接吻十招》　- 闭嘴
- 10 better ways to be a better kisser." - Shut up.
《你不了解的男人的十件事》
"10 things you don't know about him."
使劲打我　用点力气
Come on, hit me harder. Hit me, come on.
钢铁男人　你是伤害不了的
You can't hurt the man of steel. Come on, honey.
我需要这杂志
I need them.
好吧
- Okay.
钢铁男人　该把箱子带到车库了吧
Is the man of steel gonna finish taking the boxes out of the garage or what?
好
- Okay. - Ooh.
我爱你
I love you.
我要走了　我爱你
I've got to go. I love you.
我要走了
I've got to go.
喂
Hey.
早点回家
Come home soon.
好
Yeah.
嗨　桑尼
Hey, Sonny.
你好
How are you doing?
喂　大卫　和我们一起打球吧
Hey Dave, can you quarterback for us?
不行　我还有事
Can't, man. I've got to go.
喂　你刚搬来一周
Yo, man, you just moved in here a week ago.
怎么别人都已经知道你的名字了?
How the fuck does everybody know your name already?
- 你怎么老烦他　- 这是本事
- Why you always riding him? - it's a gift.
只有个性出众　有吸引力的人才有
I'm blessed with an outstandingly magnetic personality.
你也就能说罢了
Big fucking mouth you mean.
好吧　不近人情的家伙　等你将来看见美女
Okay, Mr. Antisocial. Next time you're standing next to some chick
想泡她的时候　会需要我这张嘴的
trying to get laid, you're gonna need my big mouth.
得了吧
Yeah.
泡妞还用得着你帮忙?
The day I need you to help me get laid--
你老婆都对我眉来眼去呢
I see the way your woman looks at me.
你用眼睛强奸我吗
Are you eye-fucking me, boy?
没
No, dog.
我在监狱长办公室的朋友说　到下周
My man in the warden's office says they gonna be putting your ass
就把你转移到普通监狱　到时会有人强奸你的
back in general next week. Then it's gonna be on, motherfucker.
去你的　黑鬼　我怕个屁
Fuck you, nigger. Anytime.
你很牛X啊
You's a real tough motherfucker now, huh?
所以才把你关押在C区
That's why they got your ass over there in C-block.
那是关押娘们和叛徒的地方
That's where they keep all the bitches and snitches.
你是其中哪种人
Which one you be?
喂
Hey!
你还有话要说吗　黑鬼?
You got something to say now, nigger?
谁才是娘们啊　混蛋?
Who's a bitch now, you motherfucker?
怎么不说话了啊
You want to run your mouth now, nigger?
说啊　大点声　我听不见
Come on, I can't hear you. Come on, motherfucker.
说啊　我随时都可以收拾你
Run your mouth. I'll fuck you anytime, man.
- 随时都可以　- 闭嘴
- Any fucking time. - Shut up!
闭上你的嘴　闭上你的嘴
Keep your mouth shut. Keep your mouth shut.
我们到普通监狱再见
Hey, general population, I'll see you there.
别老抱着酒瓶　你到底喝不喝了
Hey, you gonna nurse that bottle or are you gonna drink it?
怎么　你等不及了?
What, you in a hurry, man?
给我　我喝两口暖暖
Pass that shit. I need to warm up.
我还记得你第一次
I was just remembering the first time
见我爸爸的时候
Dave ever met my pop.
吓得都要尿裤子了
Dude, I thought he was gonna shit himself.
记得吗　你说话都结巴了
You remember that? You were stuttering.
很…很高兴见到你　先…先生
You were like, "N-n-n-nice to meet you, s-sir."
去你的吧
Fuck you. Whatever, man.
我不笑话你怕他　我也怕他
I don't blame you for being scared, man. I've been scared of him too.
这老头很凶的
Could be a mean old son of a bitch.
他只是说话凶
Nah, he was just all talk.
你就是这样　也就嘴上能说
All talk? That's all you've been doing is talking.
快喝吧
Start drinking.
- 天　这里真冷　- 冷死了
- Man, it is cold up here. - Fucking freezing.
嗨　嗨
Hey, man, hey.
知道我为什么喜欢来这里吗
You know why I love being up here, man?
到这里就心胸开阔了
It's just like being above it all, man.
一切困难都看得淡了
Like no problems pressing down on my shoulders.
你如果心里有疙瘩　我可以开导你
Hey, like if you need counseling, I've got you covered.
- 不过　你能让我喝两口吗　- 去你的
- But can I have the bottle? - Yeah, right.
什么假期啊
Man, fuck the holidays, dude.
高兴点
Lighten up, man.
别难过　哥们　我们爱你
Come on, bro, relax. We love you, man.
来　拥抱一下
Come on, hug it out. Rrr.
哥们　放开我
Dude, get the fuck off of me, man.
我就知道他来这套
I knew he wasn't going for that.
我们走吧　明天还有事呢
Come on, let's bounce. We've got work tomorrow.
? I won't fade out, I won't back down ?
I We're gonna raise up from the underground ?
? Now sing it with me now, say it with me loud ?
? I'm not going to fade... ?
把音乐关掉吧　烦死了
We got to turn this shit off. it's annoying.
喂　几点了
Hey, man, what time is it?
距离你上次问我　过去了5分钟
Five minutes past the last time you asked me, man.
别紧张
Chill the fuck out.
他迟到了
He's late, man.
是啊
Yeah.
- 他来了　- 我们干
- Shit, there he is. - Let's do this.
下车　趴在地上别动　否则就宰了你
Get out. Stay on the ground or I'll kill you.
别逼我砸破窗户
Don't make me break this fucking window.
趴下
Get down!
出来　宝贝　出来
Come here, sweetheart. Come here.
- 别开枪　我只是送货的　- 你闭嘴
- Don't shoot. I'm just a courier. - You shut the fuck up.
我只是送货的　别杀我
I'm just a courier. Don't kill me.
拿去吧　别伤害我
- Take it, take it. Don't hurt me. - Shut up!
- 别开枪　- 别再看我
- Don't shoot! - Quit looking at me.
你闭嘴
You, shut the fuck up!
别开枪　我只是送货的
Don't shoot! I'm just a courier!
我们走　离开这儿
Let's go, let's go! Let's fucking get out of here!
快走　我们离开这里
Come on, let's go. Get the fuck in here!
我们必须走　快
We've gotta move! Come on!
快上车
Get in here!
快上车　快
Get the fuck in! Dude, let's go.
快点　我们必须走了
Let's fucking get out of here! We've got to fucking go, man!
快　快
Come on. Fuck, come on.
你是怎么了　文斯
What the fuck's gotten into you, Vince?
杀那个人　不是我们的计划
Killing that guy wasn't part of the plan.
我和你说话的时候看着我
Look at me when I'm talking to you.
不必杀人的
Nobody was supposed to die, man.
他已经躺在地上　我控制了局势
He was fucking laying there. I had the situation under control.
不杀他　他就会
You think I want that guy out there looking for us
找机会给我一枪
trying to put a bullet in my head?
在我看来　我也是帮你们一个忙
Come on, man. The way I see it, I was doing you a favor.
帮忙?　那我以后不需要你帮这种忙
A favor? Well, try not to do me any more fucking favors, all right?
两位　两位
Ladies, ladies.
你俩别这么亲热了
Look, no kissing on the first date, okay?
哥们　你…
Dude, what does that--
已经发生的事无法改变了
Look, I just-- what's done is done, okay?
- 我们需要团结　- 对
- We've just got to stick together. - Yeah.
这个笨蛋
Stupid.
- 你的人呢　- 他会来的
- Where's your guy? - He'll be here.
他知道我们会到废弃的卡车站?
You tell him we'd be down here by the old truck depot?
他知道
Yeah, I told him.
- 他知道是河边的卡车站　- 对　他知道
- You say down by the river? - The river, yeah.
这一天我们等了很久了
Come on now, we've been waiting for this day for a long time.
就别再搞砸了
Let's not fucking fall apart.
你们来看看
Yo, come check it out.
500万美元
- Five milly. - Whoo!
天　这么多钻石　500万呢
Holy shit, that's a lot of ice, man. Five million.
看见我为什么那么做了吧　我保护了你们
See, now you see why i did what i did, man. I got y'alls back.
他来了
Here he comes.
你俩在这儿等着
Why don't y'all wait here?
500万美元呢
$5 million, man.
足够我养活老婆了
I can take care of my girl.
你整天就知道想着你老婆
That's all you think about. Valerie this, Valerie that.
- 你想要什么　- 我等着这笔钱
- What do you want? - I'm waiting on that money.
- 你怎么样　- 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
你真要这么做?
You sure?
没别的办法
Like I got a choice.
Oh!
- 你干什么　- 对不起了　哥们
- What the fuck are you doing? - I'm sorry, bro.
走　走
Let's go! Let's go!
在我躺着喘不过气来的时候
As I laid gasping for my next breath,
我知道上帝给了我第二次机会
I knew God had given me a second chance.
但我愚蠢的放弃了
But I was too stupid to take it.
当时只想得到我的东西
I was going to get what was mine.
桑尼　怎么回事
Sonny, what the fuck?
- 天　- 他对我开枪
- Fuck! - He shot me.
- 谁　- 文斯
- Who shot you? - Vince, man.
没开玩笑吧　坐下
Are you fucking kidding me? Sit down.
- 哪里中枪了　- 上面
- Where'd you get hit? - Up top.
躺下　躺下
Lay down. Lay down.
天
Oh fuck.
嵌入你的锁骨里了
It's lodged in your collarbone.
你手脏　拿开　让我看看
Get your fucking dirty hands out of there. Let me have a look.
你命大　子弹打中了你的十字架　我摘下来
You got lucky. Looks like it hit your cross. Let me get this off.
- 我妈给我的　- 我知道
- My mom gave me that. - Yeah, I know.
等一下　你需要喝两口
Hold on, you're gonna need this. Here.
因为会很疼的
'Cause this is gonna pucker your asshole.
拿开　准备好了吗
Move this. Ready?
啊
Oh shit.
没那么深
It ain't even that deep.
火辣辣的
It's fucking burning, man.
我听说出事了
I heard something was gonna go down.
没想到是你们干的
I didn't think it was you guys.
你听说什么了
What did you hear, Joe?
让我先把这事干完
Come on, let me finish this shit, all right?
啊
Ahh! Shit!
就在里面　坚持住
Fuck, it's in there. Hold on.
我看见了　感觉到了
I see the shit. I feel it.
啊
Oh Shit. Shit.
别动
Hold on, hold on.
天
Oh fuck.
不错吧　可以用它做个舌钉了
Nice, huh? I'll make a nice tongue stud with that.
真不敢相信他对我开枪　你听说什么了　乔
I can't believe he shot me, man. What'd you hear, Joey?
文斯找了一个
Vince was running his mouth
很有势力的人　说他有一笔大买卖
to some connected guys downtown that he's got a big score coming.
他为什么这么说　我们没找过他们
Why would he say that? We never kick back to them.
不知道　我觉得他是寻找保护
I don't know. I think he was just trying to buy some protection.
按住　按住
Hold that there. Hold that.
去哪儿　你要躺下
Where the fuck are you going? You need to lay down.
- 我要找到他　- 是吗
- I got to find him. - Oh, yeah, genius?
你穿着有洞的血衣在大街上走?
You gonna be walking around in a bloody shirt with a bullet hole in it?
这不是往警察枪口上撞吗　脱了
Cops won't be looking for that. Take that shit off.
给
Here.
- 听着　你知道约翰・R吧　- 知道　黑社会的　有个赌场
- Listen, you know John R, right? - Yeah, made guy, runs the card clubs.
对　在伍德沃路　本周五晚上
Yeah, down on Woodward. Now I'll bet
我肯定有人会去那里
if someone was to go down there this Friday night,
他或许见过文斯　或知道他下落的人
he might run into Vince or someone who knows where he is.
- 谢谢　乔　- 等一下
- Thanks, Joey. - Hey, hold on.
尽量别再中枪了
Try not to get your ass shot again, all right?
有什么需要就回来
You need anything, you come back here.
- 好吗　- 好的
- All right? - All right.
你想谈谈吗
Do you want to talk about it?
谈什么
Talk about what?
让你来这里的原因
Whatever brought you here.
我来替朋友祈祷的
I'm here to pray for a friend.
哦
Ah.
他病了吗
Is he sick?
不他死了
No. He's dead.
原谅我问起
Forgive me for asking.
你们亲近吗
Were you close?
是的
Yeah.
情同兄弟
We were like brothers.
那你放心　他肯定去了更好的地方了
Then rest assured he is in a better place now.
你怎么能肯定　你死过吗
How do you know? You ever been dead before?
条条大路通往上帝　孩子
There are many paths to God, my son.
但愿你的路不会特别艰难
I pray that yours will not be too difficult.
（ 职业杀手）
- 给　- 谢谢
- There you are. - Thank you, sir.
漂亮的线条
Hey, beautiful lines.
是啊
Yeah.
500万美元能买很多辆这种车吧
I guess $5 million will buy you a lot of things like that, huh?
朋友　看来我们都在找同一样东西
You see, my friend, I think we are both looking for the same thing.
我不是你的朋友　也不找什么东西
I'm not your friend and I'm not looking for anything.
好吧　那我就直说了
Okay, so let's cut the bullshit, shall we?
你们拿走了我们的东西　我们想要回来
You took something from us and we want it back.
他们派了我来办这事
And I'm the guy they picked to get it back.
不过　如果你帮助我们
However, if you help us,
我们可以不追究你的责任
we are willing to overlook your part in it.
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
拜托　我只用了两天就找到你了
Hey, come on. It only took me two days to find you.
如果你不帮忙　我也找到钻石的话
And if I get those stones without your help,
我们还会见面的
we are going to meet again.
只不过到那时候　你就是一具死尸了
Except this time you won't even hear the hammer drop.
知道吗
Are we clear?
本来按他们的意思
Look, if it was up to my friends
直接杀了你算了
you'd be dead already.
但我是有耐心的人
But I'm a patient man.
给你一周时间
You've got one week, huh?
很高心见到你
It was very nice meeting you.
两位女士　你们好吗
Oh, hey, ladies. How's it going?
你们今晚去哪儿
What you guys up to tonight?
拜托　别这样嘛
Oh come on, don't be like that.
你给我打开门
Could you get that door for me, big man?
没问题
Sure, no problem.
你打牌别这么没用好不好
Why don't you stop playing like such a fucking nit?
- 我不跟　- 你就闭嘴吧
- I'm out. - Shut your trap, you fuck stick.
你把钱拿去吧
In fact, take that.
把手举起来
Put your hands where I can see 'em.
- 你要抢劫我们吗　- 别高兴的太早
- Are you robbing us? - Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
你知道你招惹的是谁吗
Who the fuck do you think you're talking to?
重新开始谈
All right, now let's start over.
好吧　你有何贵干
Okay, what can we do for you?
这样才对　我在找文斯・朗
Now we're getting somewhere. I'm looking for Vincent Long.
- 谁见过他吗　- 没有
- Anybody seen him? - No.
谁都会有健忘症
Of course everyone's got amnesia.
但如果你们记起来的话
But if you get your memory back,
告诉他　有个老朋友在找他
tell him an old friend is looking for him, all right?
现在再抢劫你们
And now I'm robbing you.
- 你小子看什么　- 没什么
- What the fuck are you looking at? - Nothing.
- 你们怎么样　- 挺好
- How's everything over here? - Very good.
好的
Okay? Good.
- 吃完了?　- 对　吃完了
- All done? - Yeah, I'm finished.
- 结账吧　- 好
- I just need the check, please. - Okay.
给
Here you go.
今晚顾客不多啊
Slow night tonight, huh?
是啊　挣钱糊口吧
Yeah well, it pays the bills.
其实我是歌手　不会再在这里干下去了
I'm really a singer. I'm not gonna be here much longer.
为什么呢
And why is that?
我每晚祈祷
Well, I pray every night
上帝给我一个唱片合同
that God gets me a record contract.
- 他听见了吗　- 当然听见了
- Does He hear you? - Of course He does.
我只要等着轮到我
I just have to wait my turn.
不　这是给你的小费
No no, that's for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你也会交好运的
Good things are coming to you too.
我保证
- I promise.
节日快乐
Happy holidays.
（ 打手 ）
能听见吗
You with me?
- 叫什么名字　- 桑尼
- You got a name? - Sonny.
是春光明媚的桑尼吗
Like in "O what a sunny fucking day we're having?"
去你的　你是谁
Fuck you. Who are you?
好了　桑尼　该睡觉了
All right, Sonny. Sleepy-time.
（ 黑帮老大 ）
你疯了吗
Are you out of your fucking mind?
是吗
Are you?
我在找一个所谓的朋友　他对我开枪
I'm looking for my so-called friend. He shot me.
- 我要找到他　- 然后对他开枪?
- I'm gonna find him. - So you can shoot him?
你白痴吗　你弱智吗
Are you retarded? Are you handicapped?
你以为到了我的地盘
You think you're gonna come into my town
不经过我的允许
and take down poker games,
就可以打扰别人打牌　开枪杀人吗
shoot whoever you want without my permission?
你说完了吗
Are you done with your speech?
别激动佩蒂
Take it easy, Petey.
对你开枪的人是谁
What's the name of the kid that shot you?
文斯　文斯・朗
Vincent. Vincent Long.
文斯・朗和约翰的人有来往?
Vincent Long that runs with John R's crew?
对他经常去玩
Yeah, he's been hanging around.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
你成功的惹恼了我的一群
You managed to piss off a very important group of people
重要的生意伙伴　也就等于你欠了我的债
that I make money with. That means you owe me now.
- 是这样吗　- 是这样的
- Is that right? - Yeah, that's right.
我说的每句话都是事实
Every fucking thing I say is right.
但我是公平的人
But I'm a fair guy.
你帮我解决麻烦
You help me out with my problem
我就帮你解决麻烦
and I can help you out with your problem.
你说
I'm listening.
我以前认识一个人　为俄国人洗钱
I used to know a guy, laundered money for the Russians.
但他的方式很有意思
But he had a funny way of counting.
每洗三块钱　他就自己留下一块钱
For every $3 he laundered he kept $1 for himself.
积攒了很多钱
Accumulated quite a stack of dollars.
200万美元
$2 million.
但后来被俄国人发现了
Only problem is the Russians found out about it
用斧子砍掉了他两条腿
and chopped both his legs off with a axe.
但没有找到钱
But they never found the money.
他的家人把钱和尸体一起埋了
His family buried it with him.
我可不去挖什么尸体
Well, I ain't digging up no motherfucking dead body.
闭嘴
Shut the fuck up.
我不让你挖尸体
I don't want you to dig anyone up.
俄国人找到了钱在哪里
The Russians found out where the money is.
他们今晚要挖出来
They're gonna take it out of the ground tonight
你要把钱抢过来
and you're gonna take it from them.
对我有什么好处呢
What's in it for me?
很少有人知道自己的命值多少钱
Very few men know the exact value of their life.
现在你知道你的命值多少钱了
Now you know what yours is worth.
200万美元
$2 million.
为了确保你能把钱带回来
And just to make sure you bring that money to me,
我会派佩蒂和你一起去
I'm gonna send Petey along with you.
出去吧
Get out of here.
他们来了
Okay, there they are.
放松　等他们挖出来
Kick back, relax. We'll let them dig it up.
你有什么计划吗
Hey, you got a plan?
计划?　有　计划很复杂
A plan? Oh yeah, the plan's real complicated.
你偷偷溜过去
You're gonna sneak your ass down there
打死那几个混蛋　抢过钱来
and shoot those motherfuckers in the head and grab the money.
然后你就跑回来
Then you're gonna run your ass back up here like a crack nigger
越快越好　明白了吗
at a police funeral. You down with that, homie?
那你在哪儿
And where you gonna be at?
在你不远处　你办砸了就一枪打死你
Oh, close enough to shoot you in the head if you fuck up.
我带了钱来　怎么保证你不会杀了我?
What's to stop you from shooting me after I bring you the money?
这就需要你赌一把了
That's what we call a calculated risk.
Ssst
好　挖到钱了
All right, they got it.
去抢钱吧
- Let's go. Go get it. - Shit.
跪下
Get down.
拿到了
Got it.
给了你200万美元　你还是要打死我?
I get your $2 million and you're still gonna shoot me?
不
No.
但我不能一边开车　一边监视你
But I can't watch you and drive this car at the same time.
需要你把枪交出来
I need that other gun.
谢谢　桑尼　你没事了
Thanks, Sonny. You're all right.
你真有胆
You've got some balls.
你现在不用担心了
You don't have to worry about your problem now.
比格斯是言而有信的人
Mr. Biggs is a man of his word.
虽然你开始惹了她
I know you two got off on the wrong foot.
但你完成了任务　拿到了他要的钱
Hey, you did the job, we've got his cash.
我们去庆祝一下吧
Shit, let's celebrate.
你知道哪里能买到大麻吗
Know anyplace where we can get a bag?
我认识几个人　打电话联系一下
I know a few people. Let me make some phone calls.
买两包
Make it happen.
喂　哥们　我是桑尼
Hey, what's up? It's Sonny.
我知道
Yeah yeah yeah, I know.
我想去你那里　买点东西
Hey, I want to stop by there. You know, got to get a little something.
好　好的
All right. All right, cool.
你把钱留在后备箱里?
You're just gonna leave the money in the trunk?
是啊　怕什么
Yeah, why not?
没人知道我车里有200万美元
Who the fuck's gonna know I got $2 million in my car?
你这么久才来
About time you showed up, man.
拜托
Come on, man.
这是谁
Who this?
佩蒂・G
G, Petey; Petey, G.
他是警察吗
Is he a cop?
怎么问这种傻问题
Come on, why you gonna ask me some shit like that?
我总要问问嘛
Shit, nigga, I had to ask.
你俩进来吧
Y'all come on in.
天
Damn.
你没听说战争结束了吗
Hey man, the war is over. Didn't you hear?
那要看是什么战争了
Depends on which war you're talking about.
你要买多少
How much you need?
好的　我可以安排
Oh yeah. I can handle that.
你最近可好　桑尼?
So how you been, Sonny?
还活着罢了
Hey, surviving.
这家伙什么人
What's up with this motherfucker, man?
- 生意伙伴　- 是啊　理解
- That's business. - Yeah, I can dig it.
我在这里就闻到大麻了
I can smell that weed from over here, man.
这种确实够劲
Ooh, this is that fire.
我们称之为“蛇大麻”
Now we call this that snake weed.
我有个朋友　经营一家特殊宠物店
Got a partner, man, he runs an exotic pet store--
喂　混蛋　你干什么
Hey, motherfucker. What are you doing?
这可不是玩具枪
This ain't goddamn "Duck Hunt."
激动什么　我会用枪
Relax. I can handle a fucking gun.
得了吧
I'm quite sure you can handle a gun.
我刚花了两千美元修好了扳机
But I just spent $2,000 getting them triggers dialed up.
他是你的朋友?
He's your boy, huh?
接着说　他把大麻放在蟒蛇肚子里走私
Anyway, man, he puts the weed inside of boa constrictors.
- 海关不检查一下吗　- 没有哪个笨蛋
- And customs don't check it? - There ain't nobody dumb enough
会把手伸进蟒蛇嘴里
to put their hand down no goddamn snake's throat.
而且也不值得用X光检查
They're too cheap for the X-rays.
所以摆摆手　就过海关了
So they just wave them motherfuckers on through.
天
Holy shit!
- 天　- 糟了
- Oh shit. - This is bad, man.
- 拿条毛巾　- 什么
- Get a towel. - What?
- 拿条毛巾　- 为什么
- Get a towel. - Why, man?
他已经死了
This motherfucker's dead.
- 枪里有子弹?　- 你车库里的汽车
- The fucking guns is loaded? - Man, do you keep a car in the garage
会没有汽油吗　你也听见了吧
without no gas in it? You heard me, right?
我说过别碰我的枪
I told this motherfucker. I said do not touch the guns.
可这小子非要玩火
But he wanted to be the goddamn Lone Ranger and start fucking with shit.
我可不愿承担这个责任
I am not going down for this shit.
找东西把他包起来
Get me something to wrap him up in.
我杀过两个人　但这个不是我杀的
I got two strikes. This ain't gonna be my third.
- 找东西把他包起来　- 把他带到哪里
- Get me something to wrap him up in. - Shit, where are we gonna take him?
- 我认识一个人　- 住的远吗
- I know a guy. - Is he far?
混蛋　你别再废话了好不好
Motherfucker, you got something better to do?
你说得对
No no no. You're right.
- 天　- 好
- Shit. - Okay.
你也真是的
Okay. Man, you ought to ashamed of yourself
把这个疯子带到我家里来
bringing this crazy white man to my motherfucking house.
- 你知道吗　- 帮我把他翻过来
- You know that? - Help me turn him over.
- 天　- 天
- Oh shit. - Oh shit.
- 好　- 把他抬起来
- All right. - Help me pick him up.
我再也不和你来往了
I ain't fucking with you no more, Sonny.
再也不和你来往了　1　2　3
I am not fucking with you no more. One, two, three.
天
- Oh. - Oh shit.
Damn.
好稳住好
All right, all right. Hold on. All right.
他吃了什么　这么沉
What the hell were you feeding this man?
钥匙呢
Right, where are the keys?
在他身上
He's got the keys.
在他身上?
He got the keys?
你找吧　我不愿碰他
Well, you get 'em. I ain't touching him.
我的枪
Getting my gun.
别把你的老二打掉了
Don't shoot your dick off, motherfucker.
好
Okay.
你知道我的邻居爱管闲事
You know I got some nosy-ass neighbors.
好
All right.
喂桑尼
Hey, Sonny man.
你是我哥们
Look, bro, you're my boy. All right?
我喜欢你　但你以后不要再来了
Love you, man. But don't come around here no more, all right?
对生意不好
Bad for business, man.
（ 屠夫 ）
嗨　你提前来了
Hey, you're early.
领导还在这里
The suits are still here.
- 你等会再来吧　- 好
- Come around the side in a mo. - Okay.
好吗
All right?
抓着他的腿
Grab his legs.
帮我给他脱衣服
Help me get him undressed.
他真是个大汉啊
He's a big boy, isn't he?
他的衣服怎么处理
What are we gonna do with his clothes?
后面有个炉子
Oh, there's a furnace in the back.
Hmm.
好
All right.
把箱子拿近点
Yeah, bring the bin a bit closer.
好了
There we go.
好
Right.
你知道人体有207块骨头吗
Did you know there's 207 bones in the human body?
其中27块　在头骨里
And 27 of those are in the cranium.
现代人颅容量的
Now the average cranial capacity
平均值　帮忙按一下
of modern man-- hit it, would you?
是1200毫升
--is 1200cc.
而尼安德特人颅容量
And the average cranial capacity
的平均值
of Neanderthal man
是1800毫升
is 1800cc.
很奇妙吧
I was just thinking how fascinating
在我们看来原始的洞穴人
that a creature that we think is a primitive caveman
其大脑却比现代人
actually had 27% more brains
多27％
than anyone alive today.
听着屠夫嗦的时候
As I listened to the butcher rambling on
我突然想到　文斯安排的抢劫案
it hit me-- Vince set up the score.
肯定是买通了开车的司机
So the driver must have been in on it.
只要找到她　距离找到他就近很多了
If I found her, I'd be that much closer to him.
至于佩蒂
As for Petey, well...
这么说吧　从那以后　我就再也不吃汉堡包了
let's just say there's a reason I'll never eat a hamburger again.
（ 司机 ）
在附近转转
Drive around the block.
好
Okay.
好　好　求你
Okay. Okay, please.
请别冲动
Please take it easy.
可以了　停车
This is far enough. Pull over.
请不要伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
熄火
Shut it off.
- 好　- 你叫什么名字
- Okay. - What's your name?
米亚
Mia.
你认出我来了吗
You recognize me?
没　对不起　应该认出你吗
No, I'm sorry. I don't. Should I?
一个伊朗珠宝商　在第六大道和圣达菲大道路口被抢劫
An Iranian diamond broker got jacked on the corner of 6th and Santa Fe.
是的
Yeah, that's right.
我没分到钱　他在哪儿
I didn't get my share. Where is he?
黄头发的那个?　我发誓　从那以后我就没见到他
The blonde guy? I swear I have not seen him since then.
我通过朋友认识的他
L-- I met him through some friends.
他给我5万美元　让我把这个人带到一个地方
He offered me $5,000 to take this guy to a spot.
- 胡说　- 没有　没有
- Bullshit. - No no no no.
我对天发誓
I swear to God.
说的是实话　你一定要相信我
I'm telling you the truth. You have to believe me.
我没想到我的客户会受到伤害
I did not know that my client was gonna get hurt.
他向我保证不会伤人的
He promised me that that wasn't going to happen.
我发誓说的是实话　你一定要相信我
I swear to God I'm telling you the truth. You have to believe me.
求你相信我
Please, believe me.
- 米亚　- 什么
- Mia. - Yes?
如果骗我　你就惨了
For your sake I hope you're telling the truth.
天啊
Oh God.
找到你了
Gotcha.
喂喂
Whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa.
家里没钱
There's no money in the house.
文斯・朗　你认识他吗
Vincent Long, you know him?
不　我没听说过他
No, I've never heard of him.
好吧　我认识他
Okay, yeah, I know him.
给我坐下
Sit your ass down.
先说一下你是谁
Let's start with who you are.
我叫罗塞尔
I'm Russell.
为钻石交易所工作
I work for the diamond exchange.
你的朋友来找我　问我能不能交易500万美元的未加工钻石
Your friend came to me, asked me if I could move $5 million in uncut stones.
他把钻石带来　我给他钱
He brought 'em, I paid him.
交易结束　每个人都有好处
Done deal. Everybody got their share.
不是每个人
Not everybody.
显然
Well, obviously.
- 为什么找那个女的　- 米亚?
- What's the girl's angle? - Mia?
她是我女友
She's my girlfriend.
我们需要一个能沉得住气的司机
We needed a driver who wouldn't freak out.
就把她安插在租车行里
So we planted her at the car service.
我帮不了你
Look, I can't help you.
我只负责交易钻石
I move diamonds. That's all I do.
有人没得到好处　有人被杀
People don't get their share, some guy gets clipped,
这不能怪我　喂　喂
it's not my fucking problem. Hey, whoa, hey!
- 大卫・霍尔　- 什么
- Dave Hall. - What?
照着说　大卫・霍尔　照着说
Say it, Dave Hall. Say it, God damn it.
大卫・霍尔　大卫・霍尔
- Dave Hall. - Dave Hall! Dave Hall.
被杀的不是别人
That wasn't just anybody who got clipped.
是我多年的朋友大卫・霍尔
That was my long-time friend Dave Hall.
喂　我能帮你找到文斯
Hey hey, I can help you get Vince.
- 是吗　- 是的　不是很容易
- Yeah? - Yeah, it won't be easy.
他经常去第三大道的一个地方
He's got a place he hangs out over on 3rd.
那里有几个大汉　冷血杀手
Couple of guys, tough-- real stone killers.
见到他之后　给他带个话
Now when you see him you to give him a message.
就说他高中时的老同学在找他
Tell him his old friend from high school is looking for him.
不会吧　不会吧
Oh, you're kidding me. You're kidding me, right?
还用搜身?
Really?
- 放下胳膊吧　过来　- 真是的
- Put your arms down. Come around here. - Unbelievable.
你打算怎么对付他
So what are you gonna do about this guy?
也不先打个招呼?　太没礼貌了
What, no hello? That's fucking rude.
对不起　你好
Oh, I'm sorry. Hello.
那么你打算怎么对付他
Now what the fuck are you gonna do about this guy?
他昨晚都到我家了　文斯
He came to my house last night, Vince.
我家
My house.
是你搞砸了　这是你的责任
This is your fuck up. This was your end of the deal.
- 我的责任?　- 是的
- My end? - Yes.
你要解决
Now take care of it.
你对他说了什么
What did you tell him?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我的意思是　你对他说了什么
I mean what did you tell him?
当然什么也没说　你怎么这么问
Uh, how about not a goddamn thing? What are you talking about?
我知道你是软骨头　告诉我你对他说了什么
Russell, I know how weak you are, so just tell me what you told him.
我…我什么都没说
I didn't-- I didn't say-- I didn't say anything.
你没死
You're still alive.
那你肯定告诉他了什么
That means you told him something.
我想知道到底是什么
Now I want to know what the fuck it was.
好的　你说得对
Okay, you know what? Yes.
我从一开始就告诉你
I told you from the beginning
不能出任何差错
there could be no loose ends, Vince.
你需要钱　我告诉你怎么搞钱
You needed money. I told you how to get it.
但在过程中　你搞砸了
Somewhere along the line you fucked up.
他们是你的朋友　你应该摆平
These were your friends. You should have handled it.
把他弄走　马库斯
Get that shit out of here, Markus.
真不敢相信我和你是亲戚
I-I can't believe we're related.
为了促成这件事　我陪他睡了几个月的觉
I fucked this guy for months to make this deal happen.
我原本就不喜欢你陪他睡觉这个主意
I never did like the idea of you fucking him.
你知道那是必须的
You know what we had to do, Vince.
桑尼怎么办
Now what about Sonny?
我会处理
I'm gonna handle it.
他什么表情
How did he look?
这还用问　他非常上火
How the fuck do you think he looked? He looked pissed off.
你最好心里有数　文斯
I hope you know what you're doing, Vince.
- 老大　- 托尼
- Mr. B. - Yeah, Tony?
我最开心的时候
You know, one of the greatest pleasures of my life
就是吃早餐的时候　看着报纸体育版
is eating my breakfast and reading the sports page.
我喜欢看看比赛数据
I like reading the box scores.
喜欢看看谁赢了　谁输了
I like seeing who wins, who loses.
让我消遣不是吗
It relaxes me. You know what I mean?
现在　据说
Now they say
将要不再出版报纸了
that they're gonna stop publishing newspapers
让人们在手机上
so people can read the stats and the box scores
看比赛数据
on their fucking cell phone.
谁喜欢在吃饭的时候看手机呢
Who wants to look at a cell phone when you're eating food?
太荒唐了　我觉得这是
It's ridiculous. I'll tell you what it is--
不文明的
uncivilized.
世界变了
It's a different world.
Same world,
玩具变了
different toys.
佩蒂和那小子有消息了吗
What do you hear about Petey and the kid?
还没有
Nothing yet.
不过今早抓住一个俄国人
But we grabbed one of the Russians this morning.
萨尔正在审问他
Sal's softening him up right now.
好　去看看
All right. Go take a look.
我一会就去　好吗
I'll be down there in a little bit, all right?
- 有情况就给我电话　- 好
- Give me a call if something changes. - All right.
我会的　老大
Will do, boss.
老大
Boss.
佩蒂妈妈怎么说的
What did Petey's mom say?
她没听到情况
She hasn't heard anything.
他的姐妹们也没看见他
And the sisters, no one's seen him.
这里来
This way.
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么样　萨尔　他交代了吗
How's it going, Sal? He tell you anything?
- 没说多少　- 喂　伊万
- Not much. - Hey, Ivan.
喂　兄弟
Oh. Hey, buddy.
喂　喂
Hey. Hey.
你还好吗
How you doing in there?
萨尔　这和审讯的目的背道而驰
Sal, this defeats the whole fucking purpose of interrogating him.
把人打死了　还能开口吗
How are you gonna get anything out of him if he's dead?
让我来却看见他已经死了?
You brought me all the way down here for this?
现在你要再抓个俄国人了　知道吗
Now you've got to go get another Russian, all right?
我正盼着你再来呢　孩子
I was hoping I'd see you again, my son.
你可以在上帝的门口
You can leave the burden of life
卸下生活的重担
at the door of God's house.
你真的信这一套吗　神父?
You really believe all this shit, Father?
如果上帝制造好人　那他也制造坏人吧
I mean, if He made good He also made bad, right?
你相信自由意志吗
Do you believe in free will?
就是你可以自由的
The idea that you are free
做出自己的选择
to make your own choice in this world.
当然信
Of course.
如果上帝不造出两种极端的人
Then how could you make a choice between right and wrong
你如何能在其中做出选择呢
if God did not offer the two extremes?
通往上帝的路　取决于人的能力
The path to God is based upon your ability
用人的理智和情感
as a thinking, feeling being
做出正确的选择
to make the correct decisions.
如果一切都是完美的　那你不是在世上
If everything was perfect, then you wouldn't be on earth.
你已经在天堂里了
You'd already be in heaven.
你不了解我的事　神父
You don't live in my world, Father.
上帝几乎能宽恕任何事　孩子
God can forgive almost anything, my son.
但你必须愿意接受上帝才行
But you must open your heart to Him.
天
Aw, Christ.
五分钟后回来　我要先打发这个混蛋
Back five fucking minutes, I got to deal with this asshole.
嗨　约翰
Hey, Johnny.
欢迎回来　在拉斯维加斯过得如何
Welcome back. How was Vegas?
- 热　- 是吗
- Hot. - Yeah?
是的　你还想知道什么
Yeah, what else you want to know?
- 我要和你谈谈　- 听说你遇到了鬼
-I need to talk to you. - I heard you got a problem with ghosts.
- 鬼?　- 对
- Ghosts? - Yeah.
本该死的人却没有死
People that should be dead, but ain't.
我不是说过吗　要杀人的话
What the fuck did I tell you? If you're gonna whack someone,
就在头上打两枪　这样就不会复活了
you put two in the head. That way they can't come back for you.
- 我知道　- 你知道　但你没这么做
- Yeah, I know. - You know, but you didn't do that,
所以你现在有了麻烦
did you? Now you got problems.
希望你能帮我
Yeah, I was kind of hoping you could help me out.
我已经帮你了　我摆平了警察
I already helped you out. I took care of the cops.
拜托　分给你钱了
Come on, man, you got a cut.
那是保护费　我可不愿为你送死
For protection. I ain't going to war for you, kid.
- 没让你为我…　- 给我闭嘴
- I'm not asking you to go to war for-- - You shut the fuck up.
听着　你的这个朋友　不知怎么把比格斯也牵涉进来
Listen, that friend of yours, somehow he got Biggs involved.
这样情况就大不一样了
That changed everything.
比格斯可不是好惹的　他的残忍
This guy don't fuck around. He's the most ruthless,
是出了名的　上次招惹他的人
cold motherfucker you'll ever meet. You know what happened
- 你知道什么下场吗　- 不知道
-to the last guy who fucked with him? - No.
总之他的遗体惨不忍睹
Let's just say he got a closed-casket funeral.
我帮不了你　你要靠自己了
I can't do anything on this. You're on your own.
好吧
All right.
我还要告诉你
And I'll tell you something else.
如果比格斯找到了我　我会把你交出去
If Biggs reaches out for me, I'm gonna deliver you.
这么无情?
Just like that?
这是生意
It's business.
约翰
John.
该死
Fuck.
桑尼?
Sonny?
- 嗨　- 我很同情
- Hey. - I'm sorry.
他经常说
He always said that
只要你在身边　他就不会有事
he'd be okay as long as you were there.
我会补救的
I'll make it better.
好久不见了
Long time.
才13年
Only 13 years.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
我不是来找你帮忙的
I didn't come here to ask you for your help.
那你何不进来呢
Well, then why don't you get to it?
只允许我离开牢房15分钟
They only let me out of my cage for about 15 minutes.
我是来问
I came to ask
在我杀了你儿子以前　你还有什么话
is there anything you want me to tell your son
要对他说吗
before I kill him?
如果没有玻璃　你对我这么说话
You know, if this glass wasn't between us I'd break your fucking neck
我会扭断你的脖子
- for talking to me that way! - The glass is there.
喂喂
Hey. Hey!
- 行了　走　- 你听见了吗
- That's it, let's go. - You hear that?
行了　走　走
That's it, let's go. Let's go.
- 行了　- 你是疯了
- That's it. - This crazy motherfucker.
行了　行了
All right, all right.
- 他在吗　- 是的　可是他忙着
- Is he here? - Yeah, but he's busy right--
干什么　米亚
What the fuck? Mia.
你以后还会来吗
So you gonna be around later on?
- 喂　米亚　干什么　- 让她走
- Yo, Mia, what the fuck? - Get rid of her.
- 喂　- 什么
- Hey. - What?
穿上衣服走人
Get your shit and get going.
你先走吧
I guess just go.
你真是混蛋
You're a fucking asshole.
这正是我们遇到大麻烦的原因　文斯
This is why we're in a world of shit, Vincent.
因为你总是胡闹
Because you're off fucking around
不干正事
instead of taking care of business.
你冷静　我正在解决这些麻烦
Calm down. I'm tying up the loose ends.
这些?　只有一个麻烦　就是桑尼
Loose ends? The only fucking loose end is Sonny.
文斯　你一定不要低估他
I am telling you, Vincent, do not underestimate him.
我从小就认识桑尼　他做事鲁莽
I grew up with Sonny. He's a hothead.
总是走前门
He'll always come through the front door.
那我们就等着他来敲门吧
Great, so we'll just wait for the doorbell to ring, right?
米亚　够了
Mia, enough.
需要增开备用收银台
We need a backup register open, please.
备用收银台
Backup register open, please.
你要这个?
This what you want?
所有收银员到前面来
All cashiers please come to the front.
All cashiers to the front.
门开着　文斯
-- It's open, Vincent.
不再闲聊了
We're done with the small talk, hmm?
我的钻石呢
Where are my diamonds?
我卖了
I sold them.
回答错误
Wrong answer.
来
Oh, come on.
你觉得这样好玩吗
So this is fun for you? Huh?
想再来一次吗
Want to go again?
有很多好东西可以砸呢
You have a lot of nice things here.
值得你这么做吗
Is this all worth it?
是的
Yeah, it is.
好怕怕　都是血
Ooh, scary-- blood.
给我钻石就行了
Give me my diamonds and we're done.
去死吧
Fuck you!
天　我真饿
Fuck, man. I'm starving.
回去的路上买点吃的
We'll get something on the way back home.
你想吃什么
What you in the mood for?
沙拉
Shit, like a fucking salad.
什么
What the hell?
你怎么了
What's wrong with you, man?
喂　米亚
Yo, Mia.
米亚
Mia.
天
Fuck.
米亚
Mia?
该死
Fuck.
Oh fuck.
我们必须离开这里　文斯
We've got to get the fuck out of here, Vince.
我们必须走
We've got to go.
- 我们走　- 放开我
- Let's go. - Get off me!
对不起　我们必须离开这里
I'm sorry, man. We've got to get the fuck out of here.
闭嘴
Shut up.
对不起
I'm sorry, girl.
- 弗兰克　有什么情况　- 没什么　老大
- Frankie, how's it going? - Nothing, boss.
没人知道什么情况
No one's seen or heard anything.
肯定把他们两个都杀了
They must have whacked the both of them.
听着　你这愚蠢的俄国混蛋
Listen, you stupid fucking Russian son of a bitch,
如果你不想被淹死的话
if you're not gonna plan on growing gills anytime soon,
我建议你把知道的都说出来
I'd suggest you tell the man what he wants to know.
黑人拿走了钱
Black man took the money.
我只看到这些　他拿走了钱
That's all I see. He took it.
我赌十块钱　把他拉起来的时候　他会喊上帝
10 bucks says when he comes up for air he starts screaming about God.
- 赌二十块　- 成交
- 20. - Bet.
拉他上来
Bring him up.
上帝啊
Oh, mother of God!
喂　潜水员
Hey, Aqualung.
我告诉你　上帝不在这里
Let me tell you something. God ain't here.
上帝已经离开了底特律
Okay? God has left Detroit.
我是今天唯一的上帝
I'm your only god today.
所以你最好告诉我佩蒂的下落
So you'd better tell me what happened to my boy Petey,
那个黑人的下落
what happened to the black man,
以及我的钱的下落
and what happened to my fucking money.
- 听见了吗　- 一个拿枪的拿走了你的钱
- You hear me? - Man with gun, he took your money.
他拿走了你的钱　我说的是实话　是实话
He took your money. I tell the truth. I tell the truth!
你真是嘴硬啊
You're a tough son of a bitch.
再泡泡　托尼
Back in the pool, Tony.
- 你看了昨晚的球赛了吗　- 看了
- You see that game last night? - Yeah.
那个球偏出了很远
It was a ball. Way outside.
绝对不是个好球
No fucking way that was a strike.
裁判走到本垒板上　什么也看不见
Ump walked to the plate, he couldn't see shit.
- 应该用电脑的　- 对
- They should use that computer box. - Yeah.
- 偏的太多了　- 裁判就跟近视眼似的
- Way outside. - Fuckin' ump is like Mr. fucking Magoo.
什么都看不见
He can't see anything.
我觉得他淹死了　老大
I think he's drowning, boss.
拉他上来
Pull him up.
我觉得他死了
--I think he's dead.
看来他说的是实话
I think he was telling the truth.
把这里收拾完了　就来找我
Listen, come and get me after you clean this up.
- 我去按摩　- 好的　放他下来
- I'm gonna go get a massage. - Will do. Let's get him.
喂　我会到的　只是晚几分钟
Yeah? Yeah, I'll be there. I'm just running a few minutes late.
- 我不喜欢干等着　- 随便你
- I don't like to be kept waiting. - Whatever.
- 钱不够　- 都在里面了
- You're light. - it's all there.
不　钱不够
No it isn't. You're light.
你想说什么　桑德斯
What the fuck are you trying to say, Saunders?
监狱长说涨价了
The warden said the price went up.
不　我们谈妥了价钱
No no no. We had a deal.
对　你只交了一年的保护费
Yeah, you paid for a year's worth of protection.
今年的价钱更高
And now you're gonna have to pay more.
要想让你父亲保护性监禁的话
You want the old man kept in protective custody?
就要交10万美元　预付款
You pay $100,000 upfront.
这是胡闹
This is bullshit.
把你父亲关在普通监狱
How long do you think that old man's
你觉得他能活几天
gonna stay in the general population?
不超过两天　那帮囚犯就会给他一刀
I give him two days before the brothers cut him a new one.
你希望这样吗
You want that on your head?
我知道对家人好　那就做正确的事
I know you're about family, so do the right thing, Vince.
做个孝子
Be the good son.
开枪之前　你最好想清楚了
You'd better think this through before you pull that trigger.
你惹怒了我们
You fuck up with us
你父亲就是地上的一滩血
and your old man's a stain on the floor.
知道吗
Got it?
给你24小时
You got 24 hours.
否则我们就把他喂给野兽
Or we feed him to the animals.
下车
Get out.
米亚死了
Mia's dead.
你想让我说什么
What do you want me to say?
随便说什么都行
Say fucking something. Anything.
没什么可说的
There's nothing to say.
也不问她怎么死的?
You don't even want to know how?
怎么死的无所谓
It doesn't fucking matter.
你犯了一个又一个的错误
You're out there making mistake after mistake.
却不明白她为何死了?
And you wonder why she's dead?
我哪有做错了?
What am I doing wrong?
桑尼就是一个
Well, Sonny for one.
你怎么知道桑尼的事
How do you know about Sonny?
他来找过我
He came to visit me.
他就坐在你坐的地方
He sat right where you're sitting right now
在玻璃的另一边　直视我的眼睛
on the other side of this glass and he looked me in the eye.
你能行吗
Can you do the same?
我已经尽力了
I'm doing my best.
但还不够
Well, it's not good enough.
我还能怎么办
What am I supposed to do?
你真是没用　你知道吗
You really are a little shit. You know that?
我真不想说这句话
I never thought I'd have to say that.
大人物要有大动作　文斯
Big men make big moves, Vincent.
你是大人物吗
Are you a big man?
嗨
Hey.
我知道比格斯会到处找我
I knew Biggs had to be hot on my trail.
拿走别人200万美元
You don't take $2 million from a guy like that
没有谁会算了的
and expect him to forget about it.
不　你再对我解释一遍
No no, you've got to explain it to me again.
对你开枪的人杀了佩蒂
The same guy that shot you whacked Petey,
拿走了我的钱　你希望我相信是这样?
took my money, and you want me to believe that?
是的
Yes.
我对你说过　你第一次抓到他的时候　我就在找他
I told you I was looking for him when you first grabbed me, remember?
如果我拿了你的钱　我还会坐在这里吗
You think I'd be sitting here if I had your money?
我不是傻子
Shit, I ain't crazy.
怎么了
What?
- 我的钱呢　- 在文斯那里
- Where's my money? - Vincent has your money.
你的朋友文斯?
Your friend Vincent?
是的
Yes.
我知道文斯在哪里　知道钱在哪里
I know where Vincent is and I know where the money is.
但有个困难　他身边人很多
There's just one problem. He's got an army around him.
一群拿着手枪的少年犯?
An army of juvenile delinquents with pistols?
让你的人跟着我　我们去把钱要回来
Give me some of your men and we'll go get the money and bring it right back.
我有个别的办法　来
I have a different plan. Come on.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah, I'm cool.
真不要紧?
You sure?
好
All right.
喝酒吗
You want a drink?
不用了
No thank you.
会有助于你放松
Might help you relax a little.
为什么有钱人总是让我放松
Why is it rich people are always telling me to relax?
因为你年轻　你是年轻人
'Cause you're young. You're a young man.
年轻人总希望事情
Young guys just want to run through their life
办的越快越好
as fast as they can.
干完一件再干一件
Set it up, knock it down. Set it up, knock it down.
年轻是很短暂的
It's short, real short.
到了我这个年龄　你就发现多么短暂了
You get to be my age you see just how short it is.
年龄越大　就离死亡越近
The older you get, the closer you get to your death,
要放松　慢慢来
you want to relax. You want to take your time.
不要着急　年轻人
There's no rush, kid.
你真不喝吗
You sure you don't want that drink?
我喝一点吧
Yeah, I'll take a drink.
- 波旁威士忌还是苏格兰威士忌-　 波旁威士忌
- Bourbon or Scotch? - Bourbon.
干
Crap.
你要知道　我讨厌这个叫约翰的
You should know I hate this John R prick.
到了之后　让我来说　好吗
Just let me do the talking when we get there, all right?
喂　你常去教堂吗
Hey, you go to church?
以前常去
I used to.
后来慢慢的　教堂的人不想再看见我了
It got to a point they didn't want to see me there anymore.
我还是经常为教堂捐款
I still help them out with donations.
我能看到台上的牧师出冷汗
I could see those priests up there sweating.
他们看到我紧张
I made them nervous.
那么你信仰上帝?
So you believe in God?
可能不是他们所说的上帝
I don't know if I believe in their God.
是的　我也祈祷
Yeah, I pray.
每晚都祈祷
I pray every night.
我需要特别能宽恕的上帝
I need a God that's got a lot of forgiveness.
不过你不会有事的
You're gonna be all right though.
什么也不用担心
Don't worry about a thing.
怎么了　文斯　你的表情就像见鬼了
What's the matter, Vince? You look like you've seen a fucking ghost.
- 知道我们的来意吗　- 我知道
- You know why we're here, John? - Yeah, I know.
这就是你想见到的人
That's the kid you wanted to see.
给你送到了
Consider him delivered.
我的钱呢
Where's my money?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
把他的钱给他　文斯
Give him his fucking money, Vince.
不知道他对你说了什么　但都是胡说
I don't know what this dude told you, but it's bullshit.
最后一次机会
Last chance.
我尊敬你　知道你的能耐
With all due respect, I know exactly who you are
决不会拿你的钱
and I would never fucking steal--
真是的　冷静
Jesus Christ! Take it easy.
大家都别冲动　真是的
Everybody just take it easy. God damn it.
这是为佩蒂偿命
That's for Petey.
如果他的钱在你那里　你马上给他
You got something of this man's, you give it to him now.
否则人人都可能会死　约翰
Or we could all die, John.
该死
Shit.
喂
Oh! Hey!
让开
- Move!
看着点
Watch out.
该死
Fuck!
桑德斯　不要转移我爸爸
Saunders, don't you fucking move my dad.
我拿到钱了　一小时后就到
I've got your money and I'll be there in an hour.
你要出门?
Going somewhere?
你是谁
Who the fuck are you?
我不想谈这个话题
That's not the topic.
那你想谈什么话题
All right, what is the topic?
钻石
Diamonds. Mm-hmm.
是的　坐下
That's right. Sit down.
坐下
Sit down!
在有的国家　小偷会被砍手
You know, in some countries they cut off the hand that steals.
你偷了我们的东西
And you stole from us.
因此在我看来　你有三个选择
So the way I see it, you have three choices:
你可以不承认
you can fuck around,
那我会杀了你
in which case I kill you;
你可以拿桌子上的枪
you can go for that gun on the desk
我也会杀了你
and I kill you;
或者你把钻石给我
or you can just give me the diamonds
我允许你远走高飞
and I'll let you disappear.
得了吧
Yeah right.
听着　我的朋友
Look, my friend,
你远远不如你的女友硬朗
you're not half as tough as your little girlfriend.
而且到了最后
And at the end
她还是交代了
she talked.
那你如何选择呢
So what is it going to be?
她不是我的女友
She wasn't my girlfriend.
她是我的亲戚
She was my family.
便宜你了　混蛋
You got off easy, motherfucker.
快死的感觉不舒服吧
isn't much fun dying, huh, Vince?
开始挖
Start digging.
开什么玩笑
Are you fucking kidding me, man?
让我挖自己的坟墓吗
You want me to dig my own goddamn grave?
别逼我再说一遍　我让你挖
Don't make me say it again. I said start digging.
而且挖深点　让你躺着舒服点
And make sure it's deep so you're comfortable.
你想要多少钱
How much do you want?
对你来说　我这条命值多少钱
Huh? How much is my life worth to you?
老鼠皮只对老鼠有价值
A rat's skin is only worth something to a rat, Vince.
别胡说了
Man, bullshit. Come on.
你凭什么看不起我
Who are you to judge me?
有没有想过　要不是我　你会是什么样?
You ever thought about where the fuck you'd be without me?
我想过
Yeah, I thought about that
在我以为要死在你枪下的时候想过
when I thought I was taking my last breath.
是谁联系别人
Man, who was the one out there making contacts,
安排抢劫案　而你和大卫只是抽大麻?
setting up scores while you and Dave was getting high?
是我
Huh? Me.
是谁带你干这一行
Who was the one who brought you in on shit,
让你挣钱　帮你养活你妈?
put money in your pockets, helped you support your moms?
- 是我　- 这正是我不明白的
- Me! - That's what I don't understand, man.
这正是…
That's what--
我们就像一家人　就像兄弟
We were family, man. We were brothers.
- 你、我和大卫…　- 去大卫的吧
- You, me and Dave-- - Fuck Dave, dude.
那个口吃的混蛋
Come on. That stuttering little bitch.
关键是我们
This is about us, man.
他的口风那么不紧　早晚会害死我们的
How long before him and his big-ass mouth would have got us all whacked?
他忠诚
He was loyal.
他软弱
He was weak.
他是我的朋友
He was my friend.
就像你一样　文斯　记得吗
Just like you, Vince. Remember?
该死
Oh fuck.
作为你的朋友　我告诉你　桑尼
Let me tell you something as your friend, Sonny.
你在世上得到的一切　都是因为我
Everything you got in this world is because of me.
你能有今天
Everything you fucking are in this world
都是多亏了我
is because of me.
你到底遇到了什么麻烦
What could you have gotten into
连我都不能告诉?
that was so bad that you couldn't tell me?
告诉我　我想知道
Huh? Tell me, I want to know.
我从小就护着你
I had your back since we were kids, man.
可你呢　你开枪打我　任由我去死
And what do you do? You fucking shoot me and leave me for dead.
我没别的办法　我遇到大麻烦
I had no choice, man. I was in over my head.
我需要全部的钱
I couldn't-- I needed all the money.
他们会…他们会杀了我爸爸
They were gonna-- they were gonna kill my father.
- 什么　- 他们会杀了我爸爸
- What? - They were gonna kill my dad.
桑尼　你说得对
Sonny, you're right, man.
对不起　我该找你帮忙的
And I'm sorry. I should have come to you.
你一定要告诉我　我现在该怎么办
But you-- you've gotta tell me, what can I do right now?
怎么补救　告诉我
How can I make this right, man? Tell me what to do.
现在已经太晚了
You should have thought about that before.
你找上帝原谅你吧　不要找我
You make peace with God, not me.
来吧
Do it.
来吧　桑尼　对我开枪
Fucking do it, Sonny. Shoot my ass.
要不是我　你什么都不是
'Cause you know what? You ain't nothing in this world without me, man.
打死我　我们就一样了
You shoot me and we're the same.
我们都会死了
We'll both be gone.
我们不一样
We're not the same.
你真可悲
You're fucking pathetic, man.
去你的
Man, fuck you!
Fuck you, man!
我不需要你　桑尼
I don't need you, Sonny.
我不需要你　你需要我
I don't need you, man. You need me.
你需要我
You need me!
我会走出去的　你会看到
I'm gonna walk out of here. You'll see, man.
听见了吗　听见了吗
You hear me? You hear me?!
去你的
Fuck you!
我会找到你的
I'll find your ass!
去你的　桑尼
Fuck you, Sonny!
喂　看　看
Yo, man, check it out. Check it out.
很高兴认识你
Yo, it was nice knowing you, buddy.
分开　让开
Break it up! Make a hole!
后退　后退
- Get back! Get back! - Back off!
- 后退　- 马上派医生来
- Back off! -I need a medic in Red.
- 后退　- 后退
- Back up. - Get back.
Get back on the wall. Get back.
我看看你们的手　把手伸出来
Let me see your hand. Get your hand out of there.
- 你好　- 你好
- How are you doing? - Hi.
请在这里签收
I need you to sign right here.
（ 看里面　爱你的大卫 ）
? How do you want to be remembered? ?
? For your honor ?
? Or your pride? ?
? How do you want to be remembered? ?
? For you body ?
? Or your mind? ?
有人说过　冤冤相报的话
A man once said an eye for an eye
人人都会死
leaves everyone blind.
就像我不是我兄弟的守护者一样
As I was not my brother's keeper,
我也不是杀他的人
neither was I his killer.
我能够接受文斯还活着的事实
I could live with the fact that Vincent was still alive.
问题是　他能接受吗
The question was, could he?
? Time is on my side ?
? And still the world continues to turn ?
? And as I think about the things that I've learned ?
? I see that money's worth less ?
? With every dollar I earned ?
? And in the end I'd rather choose to fade than burn ?
? Sometimes you pay the price ?
? For flying close to the sun ?
? But that's why youth is wasted on the young ?
? I think of all the things that I've done?
? All the ghosts in my past ?
? Will my reputation live, will it crumble and crash? ?
? As I dream I see a vision of an angel who asks ?
? Why'd I die young and leave a pretty face in the casket? ?
? Ain't no fashion here, we don't take plastic ?
? We don't give a damn how many chips you cashed in ?
? With ashes I'm waiting at the entrance to heaven ?
? Without a legacy, why should they show me acceptance??
? Though she doesn't speak ?
? I hear the words of her lessons ?
? And as she sings, she haunts me ?
? With the simplest of questions, she says ?
? How do you want to be remembered? ?
? For your anger ?
? Or your love? ?
? How do you want to be remembered? ?
? For your beauty ?
? Or your blood? ?
? How do you want to be remembered? ?
? For your actions ?
? Or your words? ?
? Too big a sacrifice ?
? How do you want to be remembered? ?
? For your silence ?
? Or your voice? ?
? Leave a legacy. ?
ripped from blu-ray by gioni666